Doctor
I have a question for you.
What type of person
is most likely to experience acid reflux?
Yeah, people who eat irregularly.
No, it's not.
People with acid reflux
are most attracted to banquets.
Yeah, really.
People who eat banquets
yes
Because when you eat the tenth course
started
having acid reflux
Shí dào(transliteration)
Hahaha, that's utter nonsense!
Hu Naiwen is about to begin his lecture.
I am your old friend, Dr. Hu.
Xiè jīn yàn (transliteration) also has acid reflux.
Two acupoints for treating heartburn
Singer Xiè jīn yàn (transliteration) also suffered
suffered from gastroesophageal reflux disease.
Once
Xiè jīn yàn (transliteration) eats after dance practice
feel a foreign object in throat
A hospital checkup
revealed gastroesophageal reflux disease
I saw Xiè jīn yàn (transliteration)
reminding herself
on social media that she needs to give up late-night snacks.
If we accidentally
eat a late-night snack
and start experiencing acid reflux
How can quickly relieve the symptoms?
That's strange. Why is it called "accidentally eating a midnight snack"?
You ate a late-night snack and it was by accident.
Ha ha ha ha
Just occasionally
Eat occasionally
Occasionally eating
That's fine.
Occasionally having a late-night snack
Drink a glass of warm water first
People with acid reflux
Drinking warm water is helpful
have
not telling you to gulp it down
Instead, drink it sip by sip.
Drinking warm water can dilute some stomach acid.
Reduce the irritation of stomach acid on the esophageal mucosa
Relieves burning sensation in the chest
and sore throat
Next, you can press two more acupoints.
Nèi guān (transliteration) and zú sān lǐ (transliteration) acupoints
It is very effective in preventing
and relieving gastroesophageal reflux
Let's start with the Nèi guān (transliteration)acupoint.
There's a saying in traditional Chinese medicine...
Nèi guān (transliteration), gōng sūn (transliteration), Stomach, Heart, Chest
stomach, heart, chest
When there are problems in these areas
Just look for the Nèi guān (transliteration)
Nèi guān (transliteration)
Once it's stimulated
It can immediately relieve chest discomfort
and heartburncaused
by acid reflux
Try pressing it.
It eased up quickly.
The Nèi guān (transliteration)acupoint is located
three finger-widths above the wrist crease
Between the two tendons
Press it gently here
That can improve things a lot.
How long should we press
until we feel more comfortable?
Don't press for too long.
Just two or three minutes will do
People with acid reflux
Are they also more prone to constipation?
Possibly
I have seen many patients like this
There is an acupoint that is very useful.
That is zú sān lǐ (transliteration)
It is below the knee.
About the length of four fingers
The position that is one finger's
width away from the tibia
That's called zú sān lǐ (transliteration) acupoint
You are prone to bloating and constipation
Press the zú sān lǐ (transliteration)acupoint frequently
It will be very helpful
woken up by stomach acid in the middle of the night
3 behaviors to avoid
Gastroesophageal reflux disease most commonly occurs
during these two time periods
After eating
How to stop it
after lying down at night
Gastroesophageal reflux disease
The first is 2 hours before bedtime.
Don't eat anything
If
I go to bed at 12 o'clock at night.
You can't eat anything
after 10 PM
Is it better to go to bed earlier?
Wouldn't it be better
if you didn't eat anything after 7 o'clock?
7 o'clock
Because you can go to sleep
around 9 or 10 o'clock, right?
That's right
Half an hour to two hours after eating
This is when stomach acid
secretion is at its peak
and digestion is in progress
You should lie down now
Stomach acid will then easily rise to the top.
In addition, how you eat is also very important.
Take at least twenty or thirty bites
with each bite
Don't wolf down your food.
You eat too fast
Food particles too large
It takes the stomach more time
to digest it, right?
The pressure in the cardia area is great
Stomach acid may then flow back up.
There is another important point
People our age
should never talk
while eating
Sometimes choke
That could be dangerous.
It's true, that's right.
Second, don't lie down immediately after eating.
Why do many people experience acid reflux
s soon as they lie down after eating?
Because dinner was eaten too late
If you eat a very large meal...
The stomach hasn't emptied yet.
Stomach acid is more likely
to rise and move upwards
Come on, you can do this
Get up and move around a bit after you've eaten.
Go wash the dishes
You can at least help your wife wash the dishes, right?
Go to dry the clothes
Surely you can help your wife hang up the laundry?
Also, tidying up the house.
Or go for a walk
A walk of about ten minutes is enough.
It slowly digests the food
in the stomach
The food for the third dinner
Don't make the flavor too strong.
Don't drink too much water
I also suggest
Eat a light dinner
Beverages or water
Don't drink too much.
can greatly improve gastroesophageal reflux.
People with acid reflux
What foods should not be eaten?
Listen carefully, this is the main principle.
These 5 flavors
Too sweet, too sour, too spicy, too oily, too strong in flavor
People with acid reflux
You must eat less
Or don't eat it first.
These foods can stimulate the secretion of gastric acid.
It also increases the chance
of acid reflux
If stomach
keeps rumbling
before go to sleep
People with acid reflux
What can eat?
You asked this for yourself
be noticed
You can eat when you're hungry
Two or three soda crackers
Don't eat very sweet cookies!
can only eat two or three soda crackers
Don't eat any more!
White toast or oatmeal.
The key point
is to wait half an hour after eating
Go lie down and go back to sleep again
can't just lie down
and flatten out right after eating this
This can easily lead to acid reflux.
What's the best food for acid reflux?
Two vegetables to protect your stomach: white fungus for afternoon tea
People with acid reflux
What's the best thing to eat?
These two great vegetables
Eat it
Cabbage and sweet potato leaves
Don't be fooled by their ordinary appearance
Cabbage is a natural stomach remedy
It contains vitamin U
It can inhibit gastric acid secretion
Soothe acid reflux
There are also ways to improve
Gastric ulcer, duodenal ulcer
Wow, that's amazing!
I still remember when I was in college
The restaurant always serves cabbage
Some people were very unhappy
But in reality...
My stomach wasn't very good at that time
So it was pretty good to eat
Sweet potato leaves contain dietary fiber
It can help with intestinal peristalsis
Reduce bloating
My stomach felt much better after eating it
Gastroesophageal reflux
won't bother you anymore
So simple
Two vegetables
Is there anything
that lazy people like me can eat
certainly
Like white fungus, kelp, and yam
These gelatinous foods
It releases its gelatinous substance after cooking.
Then what
It forms a barrier on the stomach wall
that can block stomach acid
and also enhance immunity
Isn't that awesome?
That's great, so simple!
Doctor, you said white fungus
I drink it regularly too
It tastes good
It can nourish our stomach
and also make our skin
more elastic
That's really elastic
Kill two birds with one stone
Ladies who need to nourish their stomachs
You can also be like xiǎo fēn(transliteration)
Go to the supermarket to buy this
White fungus
Come and eat!
Great! Very good!
People with acid reflux
It seems like can't eat
very sour fruits
Do you have any recommendations?
Papaya Banana
These are all acceptable.
Not bad, not bad
Papaya's papaya enzyme
It can break down proteins
It also reduces the burden on the stomach
Bananas can neutralize stomach acid
Smooth and warming to the stomach
Stomach medication cannot stop acid reflux
One key to solving the root cause
People in their thirties and forties
Busy with work
When gastroesophageal reflux occurs
started taking stomach medicine
As a result, stomach acid started acting up again in the middle of the night.
That was so painful.
Right
I see a lot of people taking stomach medicine.
Especially taking that antacid
His acid reflux recurred.
Did you know?
Long-term dependence on antacids
It may also slow down digestion in the spleen and stomach.
Intestinal peristalsis then weakens further.
This can cause bloating and constipation.
Even increased intragastric pressure
Instead, it surged upwards.
This resulted in gastroesophageal reflux.
How could this be?
Western medicine inhibits stomach acid.
What methods does Traditional Chinese Medicine
use to prevent gastroesophageal reflux?
Traditional Chinese medicine does not consider stomach acid to be harmful.
Actually, it helps with digestion.
What does it help with? See?
It is known from a physiological perspective
It helps you digest the protein
you just ate
Moreover, it can kill bacteria.
Too little stomach acid can actually cause indigestion.
It also causes bloating and damages the gastric mucosa.
Even stomach ulcers
So serious
Our treatment focuses
It helps the stomach restore its original function.
The key point about gastroesophageal reflux disease is...
Wèi qì bù shùn (transliteration)
From the perspective of Traditional Chinese Medicine
normal Wèi qì (transliteration)
It is to push the food downwards.
But you eat too fast
Overeating, eating too late before bed
High stress and emotional tension
Stomach gas may rise upwards.
At this point, stomach acid reflux occurs
To truly cure the root cause, you need to nourish your spleen and stomach
To promote Wèi qì (transliteration)
Let the stomach at the right time
Doing the right thing is the best approach.
It means we shouldn't
eat too fast
Don't eat too fast, that's right.
Don't eat dinner too late.
Do not overeat
If all of these are improved
Stomach acid will then stop rising.
That's right
Wèi qì (transliteration) is flowing smoothly
Acid reflux, sour throat
sore throat, difficulty swallowing
These symptoms will gradually improve.
In addition, you are easy
People who Chǎn qì (transliteration) and have slow digestion
May be more prone to gastroesophageal reflux
First, eat less of these four types of food
Milk, cheese, beans
And refined sugar
First, stabilize the gastroesophageal reflux.
Acid reflux disease is a mood disorder
Does stress cause acid reflux?
Some people are slow and deliberate.
Take things slowly
Some people just can't stand being rushed
or slow
Can emotions affect
gastroesophageal reflux
Of course!
Traditional Chinese Medicine has
The saying about internal injury from the seven emotions
The seven emotions are seven kinds of feelings.
Joy, anger, worry, thought, grief, fear, surprise
Which emotion is too much
Both can damage the spleen and stomach
Causes gastroesophageal reflux
Especially if you are in your 40s or 50s
Busy with work during the day
still need to take care of family when get back
Replying to messages while eating
The pressure is immense; after get off work
still have to do housework and take care of the children
Gān huǒ gěi yù zhe le (transliteration)
Stomach acid tends to rise.
Research found
The greater the pressure
Gastroesophageal reflux disease
The easier it is to find you
Há(transliteration)
This acid reflux
It's a stress alarm!
How can calm it down?
Come and do these two things
The first thing
Calm down for five minutes
You can be like me.
Sit quietly before sleep
Or when you encounter a very tense situation
Take a deep breath
like this
Let your mind go blank for a while
Then let's just stand there.
Just lie down and laze around.
Is it also possible?
Of course!
I often do this.
It's about metabolizing stress.
Let the autonomic nervous system
return to its normal balance
What about the second thing?
Just keep a relaxed mood.
Chew each bite of food properly.
It means biting it twenty or thirty times.
Like giving stomach a gift of love
Take good care of yourself
So your stomach won't go on strike.
You are in a good mood
Only then can stomach feel comfortable
Dear fans
We have launched the membership channel.
If you agree with my philosophy of promoting Traditional Chinese Medicine
for taking care of one's health
Small monthly donations are welcome.
It only costs the price of two cups of coffee!
Or become a VIP sponsor
With you by my side
Only then can we go further.
Thank you so much!